Mss.Rec.186 Mss.Rec.186
American Philosophical Society
Linguistic properties of the Caddo language
1993
Mss.Rec.186
American Philosophical Society
29.0 Tape(s)
The collection comprises linguistic recordings of relating to Caddo vocabulary, phrase structure, syntax, adjectives, and sound changes. Also includes interviews and discussion of Caddo traditional songs and customs. Recorded by Lynette Melar at Binger and Gracemont, Oklahoma in September 1993 with consultants Clara Brown, Retha Cousins, and Helen Tate.
29 sound tape reels (14 hr., 45 min.): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono; 7 in.
Brown, Clara
Cousins, Retha
Melnar, Lynette
Tate, Helen
Arrangement note
Original tapes numbered 1A-15B (no 6B).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by Lynette Melnar in 1993 (Acc. 1994-320r). This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Related Archival Materials
Related manuscript materials are available in the Phillips Fund Collection (Mss.497.3.Am4).
Caddo language; Caddo language--Study and teaching; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Caddo vocabulary, phrase structure: "abandon" to "answer", 1993-09-01; 01A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:28; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Binger (Okla.); Caddo language
  - Caddo vocabulary, phrase structure: "anxious" to "autumn", 1993-09-01; 01B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:20; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo vocabulary, phrase structure, 1993-09-01; 02A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:14; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
    Binger (Okla.); Caddo language; Months
  - Caddo vocabulary, phrase structure, 1993-09-01; 02B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:26; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo vocabulary, phrase structure, 1993-09-07; 03A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:24; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo vocabulary, phrase structure, 1993-09-07; 03B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:25; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo adjectives, sound change [1 of 5], 1993-09-08; 04A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:02; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
    Scope and Contents note
    This program records a portion of a Caddo language class and includes several unidentified speakers.
    Caddo language--Adjectives; Caddo language--Phonology; Caddo language--Study and teaching; Gracemont (Okla.)
  - Caddo adjectives, sound change [2 of 5], 1993-09-08; 04B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:10; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo adjectives, sound change [3 of 5], 1993-09-08; 05A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:14; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo adjectives, sound change [4 of 5], 1993-09-08; 05B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:15; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo adjectives, sound change [5 of 5], 1993-09-08; 06A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:34; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo vocabulary, syntax: "bloody" to "break", 1993-09-13; 07A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:17; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo vocabulary, syntax: "break" to "bump", 1993-09-13; 07B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:16; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo traditional songs [1 of 4], 1993-09-13; 08A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:21; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
    This program includes several unidentified speakers.
    Caddo Indians--Music; Caddo Indians--Social life and customs; Caddo language; Gracemont (Okla.)
  - Caddo traditional songs [2 of 4], 1993-09-13; 08B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:18; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo traditional songs [3 of 4], 1993-09-13; 09A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:18; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo traditional songs [4 of 4], 1993-09-13; 09B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:27:51; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo syntax [1 of 2], 1993-09-15; 10A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:19; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
    Caddo language; Caddo language--Study and teaching; Caddo language--Syntax; Gracemont (Okla.)
  - Caddo syntax [2 of 2], 1993-09-15; 10B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:21; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo syntax and discourse [1 of 4], 1993-09-15; 11A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:49; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo syntax and discourse [2 of 4], 1993-09-15; 11B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:31; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo syntax and discourse [3 of 4], 1993-09-15; 12A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:00; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo syntax and discourse [4 of 4], 1993-09-15; 12B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:14; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo verbs, syntax [1 of 3], 1993-09-15; 13A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:48; Brown, Clara; Cousins, Retha; Melnar, Lynette; Tate, Helen
    Caddo language; Caddo language--Study and teaching; Caddo language--Syntax; Caddo language--Verbs; Gracemont (Okla.)
  - Caddo verbs, syntax [2 of 3], 1993-09-23; 13A-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:20:20; Brown, Clara; Cousins, Retha; Melnar, Lynette; Tate, Helen
  - Caddo verbs, syntax [3 of 3], 1993-09-23; 13B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:18; Brown, Clara; Cousins, Retha; Melnar, Lynette; Tate, Helen
  - Caddo verbs [1 of 2], 1993-09-23; 14A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:19; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
    Caddo language; Caddo language--Study and teaching; Caddo language--Verbs; Gracemont (Okla.)
  - Caddo verbs [2 of 2], 1993-09-23; 14B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:17; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
  - Caddo vocabulary [1 of 2], 1993-09-24; 15A-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:17; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette
    Binger (Okla.); Caddo Indians--Social life and customs; Caddo language
  - Caddo vocabulary [2 of 2], 1993-09-24; 15B-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:31:20; Brown, Clara; Melnar, Lynette